<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Iron Realms Nexus Event Bus Blog</title>
        <link>https://keneanung.github.io/@keneanung/nexus-event-bus/blog</link>
        <description>Iron Realms Nexus Event Bus Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2022 keneanung</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Initial Release v0.0.3]]></title>
            <link>https://keneanung.github.io/@keneanung/nexus-event-bus/blog/2021/04/11/_Initial_Release</link>
            <guid>/2021/04/11/_Initial_Release</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><code>Hello World!</code></p><p>And with that out of the way, I present the first release on my event bus package for the Nexus MUD client.</p><p>While there are already implementations of the event bus for the Nexus MUD client (ie as part of the NexSys and NexGUI projects), I wanted to make a package that is not part of a larger project. Instead this project can be installed individually and be used as a dependency for other projects. This should make it easier for the community to adapt a set of lightweight standard packages that still allow the users a large amount of flexibility to use the packages they like.</p><p>This release is the minimal viable product and contains the most basic functionality: Registering event handlers, raising events and unregistering event handlers. The <a href="https://keneanung.github.io/nexus-event-bus/docs/api" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">API documentation</a> has all the gritty details.</p><p>More features may be added in the future. Feel free to <a href="https://github.com/keneanung/nexus-event-bus/issues/new" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">create a new issue</a> to discuss further extnsions.</p><p>If you like my work and want to support me, please consider <a href="https://github.com/sponsors/keneanung" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sponsoring me</a>.</p><p>Oh, and why is the initial release version <code>0.0.3</code>? Well, I messed up the packaging, so I had to redo it a few times. I'm sorry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>keneanung@gmail.com (keneanung)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>